<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>NOTELISH</title>
    <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii" />
    <updated>2021-04-29T18:21:11+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>one</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Suggestions in writing</title>
        <author>
            <name>one</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/suggestions-in-writing/"/>
        <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii/suggestions-in-writing/</id>
            <category term="Writing"/>

        <updated>2021-04-29T18:21:11+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    1. Continuously maintain high quality input I recall that when I first wrote, I sat in front of the computer, scratching my ear and scratching my cheek, and I didn't know how to write. In the final analysis, my stomach had too little "ink" to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>1. Continuously maintain high quality input</h2>
<p>I recall that when I first wrote, I sat in front of the computer, scratching my ear and scratching my cheek, and I didn't know how to write. In the final analysis, my stomach had too little "ink" to hold the literati. Less "ink" means we don't have enough input. <br>Input is like the inlet of a reservoir. Only by keeping a continuous supply of input can there be a continuous flow of output. Input and output is a complete closed loop. <br><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #3598db;"><em>So what are inputs and outputs? </em></span><br>What you hear, what you learn, what you see can be called input, and what you write and say can be called output. We usually read books, read articles is a kind of input, communicate with people, get new ideas and methods, these are also a kind of input. <br>Even what you see and hear during the journey, the new things you come into contact with, is also a kind of input. <br>For example, when I read books and read other people's articles, I will encounter some golden sentences, stories and cases; chat with friends, classmates and strangers, talk about good methods, new ideas, and desirable places. I will write down, accumulate more, collect more, organize more, absorb more, and internalize more. <br>In writing, when you encounter the right topic, you can sort it out and use it, which can not only make the content of the article appear lively and interesting, but also enrich the content, so that the whole article will not be full of our own stories, so that it will be written out in less than a few times. <br>For good methods, I will also practice and experience more deeply. This is a typical use of input and output. Only by insisting on self-knowledge input and integrating into one's own practice can we make these common principles more attractive and more persuasive when they are passed on to everyone. Readers are also more willing to accept, resonate, make changes, and take action.</p>
<h2>2.Writing should think carefully, improve the depth and highlight the novelty</h2>
<p>Writing is the process of expressing ideas in words, and the words you write are the crystallization of your thinking. If your brain is empty, no matter how good your writing skills are, you can only moan without illness. The point you think out is the soul of the article. The clearer you think, the clearer you can write. A profound article comes from deep thinking. <br>There are many writers now, and when you think of a point, many Daniel writers may have written it already. No matter how good you are, it is very difficult to stand out, because when readers go to see the big names, your reading volume and attention will naturally be less. <br>When writing, you can first go to the platform or the web to search for similar topics or articles, if there is already a particularly good one, then continue to think about the theme to avoid bumping into shirts and homogenizing content. <br>Want to scarce themes or ideas and perspectives are relatively "new". <br>There are two methods that can be used. <br><em><strong>1) the exclusion method of three-tier thinking. </strong></em><br>Is to face a subject, the first layer of thinking to think of a theme, and then think of the second, and then think hard back, until come up with a new point of view. <br><strong><em>2) the method of multi-angle observation of the same subject matter. </em></strong><br>Try to analyze it from different angles, for example, excellent movies will have a lot of reviews, and everyone will cut into different angles, and the effect will be different. These are all materials for us to learn. <br>Then how to improve their thinking ability, introduce several methods, are very easy to use. <br><em><strong>1) when you encounter anything, ask yourself a few more "why".</strong></em></p>
<p>When you were a child, when you encounter something, we always like to ask a lot of why. Later, we all grew up, a lot of things, our thinking is only on the surface, no longer want to ask why, gradually, we are too lazy to think. <br>For a writer, we should constantly ask ourselves "why", dig deeper, explore the truth, pursue the deepest thoughts, force ourselves to think, and pursue the origin of things. <br><strong><em>2) A4 paper brainstorming</em></strong><br>Take a minute to write down your thoughts on A4 paper. <br>Write down the topic you want to express on each piece of paper, write 4-6 lines on a page, 20-30 words on each line, and limit the time to one minute. <br>The way to do this is to quickly focus your attention and arouse your thoughts. <br>Long-term training can easily improve the ability of deep thinking. <br><strong><em>3) use the golden circle of thinking. </em></strong><br>The way we look at problems is divided into three levels. <br><strong>The first level</strong> is the what level, that is, the appearance of things, everything we do. <br><strong>The second level </strong>is the how level, that is, how we achieve what we want to do. <br><strong>The third level </strong>is the why level, which is why we do such things. <br>The most basic application of the golden circle of thinking is: when you encounter everything, you must first ask "why" in order to know what to do and what to do. For example, when you write, you must first think about "why you want to write". Only by thinking clearly about why can you have the motivation to continue to write. <br>We should develop the habit of asking why when solving problems, and do things from the beginning to the end. If you slowly develop this habit of thinking, you will grow and gain from anything, and the effect of this ability is the most frightening and amazing.</p>
<h2>3.Continuously improve writing skills.</h2>
<p>Writing is also a skill, it takes deliberate practice to make perfect, every writing is an exercise, every time reading other people's articles, dismantling the writing methods of other people's articles, is a kind of learning. <br>Novices usually not only have to study other people's excellent works, imitate and learn; on the other hand, they should start to write boldly. Only when they really write, can they have a chance to write better and better; they can also specialize in reading books to improve their writing skills in an all-round way. <br><span style="color: #3598db;"><strong>Write more and change more. </strong></span><br>If you write less, your brain will not live; if you change less, you will not be able to express clearly. You can also read relevant writing books about improving your writing skills. I recommend that I have read several books that have a great influence on me.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Get rid of the following five misunderstandings, and you will make progress faster</title>
        <author>
            <name>one</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/get-rid-of-the-following-five-misunderstandings-and-you-will-make-progress-faster/"/>
        <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii/get-rid-of-the-following-five-misunderstandings-and-you-will-make-progress-faster/</id>
            <category term="Progress"/>

        <updated>2021-04-29T17:41:37+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Indulge in things that are "easy to get a high sense of achievement" Consciously or unintentionally seek a recipe for a great "return" with a small amount of effort, even if the reward is virtual. This kind of behavior will raise their own "excitement&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <h2 id="indulge-in-things-that-are-easy-to-get-a-high-sense-of-achievement">
      Indulge in things that are "easy to get a high sense of achievement"
    </h2>

  <p>
    Consciously or unintentionally seek a recipe for a great "return" with a small amount of effort, even if the reward is virtual. This kind of behavior will raise their own "excitement threshold", making people less and less likely to have a sense of achievement, thus relying more and more on a virtual sense of achievement and falling into a vicious circle.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    Mild symptoms:&nbsp;"addicted to games" (speeding up the passage of time in the virtual world, so that "success" comes faster), "stallion novels" (obscene people can easily get what they want);
  </p>

  <p>
    Serious symptoms and even illegal: gambling" (easy access to "money"), "drug abuse" (easy to get the feeling of "cool"), and so on.
  </p>

    <h2 id="only-receive-sources-with-low-information-densitynbsp">
      Only receive sources with "low information density"&nbsp;
    </h2>

  <p>
    Only willing to receive information with low information density (such as videos and pictures that do not need too much brainstorming, as well as shallow entertainment, gossip, sports news, etc.). Do not want to receive information with high information density and can only be absorbed after careful consideration (such as courses, knowledge frameworks, analytical reports, etc.).&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    Since most of the really valuable and progressive information needs to be considered and digested, it will not be possible to make progress without in-depth study and understanding.
  </p>

    <h2 id="get-used-to-paralyzing-yourself-with-a-sense-of-misplaced-achievement">
      Get used to paralyzing yourself with a sense of "misplaced achievement"
    </h2>

  <p>
    <br>There are two categories: first, compare your strengths with other people's weaknesses, so as to get the illusion of "better than others" (for example, compared with athletes, and high achiever compared with sports); second, when others are resting after serious work, pretend to work harder (for example, "show off" that you have done more work than others on holidays, but only on holidays).
  </p>

    <h2 id="overreliance-on-existing-feasible-paths">
      Over-reliance on "existing feasible paths"
    </h2>

  <p>
    At work, after getting used to the process of a thing, I never think about how to improve it. I will only repeat it mechanically, and then deceive myself to be full. If there is no improvement, there is no consciousness of getting rid of dross, so there are more and more things that need to be repeated and take longer and longer. in the end, it seems that a lot of things have been done every day, but in fact, there is not only no progress at all. the time of progress that should have been made is also wasted.
  </p>

    <h2 id="close-the-channel-of-reinforcement-learning">
      Close the channel of "reinforcement learning"
    </h2>

  <p>
    In learning or receiving information, you are only willing to perform the simplest first step, but are unwilling to carry out the next more complex consolidation and application process, only listening without speaking, reading without writing, learning without practice, and paralyzing yourself by saying that you have learned a lot. In fact, this kind of "shallow" learning forgets so quickly that sometimes it is better not to learn at all. For example, learn English every day, but never write English articles.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to learn faster?</title>
        <author>
            <name>one</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/how-to-learn-faster/"/>
        <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii/how-to-learn-faster/</id>
            <category term="Study"/>

        <updated>2021-04-29T11:22:35+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are two modes of the human brain The two modes are the most efficient to use alternately. If you knock yourself to death in any mode, you are doing useless work. Focused mode: your brain is mainly learning, entering information, and doing information matching&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2><span class="text-dst">There are two modes of the human brain</span></h2>
<address><strong><span class="text-dst">The two modes are the most efficient to use alternately. If you knock yourself to death in any mode, you are doing useless work.</span></strong></address>
<p><span class="text-dst"><strong>Focused mode</strong>: your brain is mainly learning, entering information, and doing information matching work. </span><span class="text-dst">It is usually started when we are working and studying.</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>Diffuse mode</strong>: your brain is doing internal analysis, generating new links, re-linking and kneading old knowledge. </span><span class="text-dst">This state is initiated when we sleep, exercise and other relaxed states. </span><span class="text-dst">Sometimes you have inspiration when you take a shower, and that's what this pattern does.</span></p>
<p><span class="text-dst"> To sum up, it is necessary to stop and play after studying for a period of time. </span><span class="text-dst">It's not laziness, but only in this way, your brain works most efficiently.</span></p>
<h2>Procrastination is normal</h2>
<p><span class="text-dst">According to scientists, when we encounter something we don't like or something very difficult, the brain secretes a special substance that makes you feel uncomfortable. </span><span class="text-dst">Then it naturally encourages you to focus on other things, and you procrastinate. </span></p>
<p><span class="text-dst">So, first of all, you have to know that procrastination is a normal human behavior, so don't blame yourself too much. </span></p>
<p><span class="text-dst">What are we going to do with it? </span><span class="text-dst">Our brains also have a magical function, that is, once you focus on a task for more than five minutes, this particular substance will stop secreting. </span><span class="text-dst">So the solution to doing unhappy things is to force yourself to start for five minutes, and then everything will be fine.</span></p>
<h2><span class="text-dst">About memory. </span></h2>
<address><strong><span class="text-dst">The content needs to be repeated constantly, and the higher the previous repetition frequency, the longer the memory will be preserved</span></strong></address>
<p><span class="text-dst">Which of the following ways can achieve a better and faster memory effect if you want to remember a poem?</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>A</strong> memorize over 20 times a day.</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>B</strong> recite 10 times on the first day, 5 times on the second day, and 5 times on the 4th day.</span><br><span class="text-dst">The answer is <strong>B. </strong></span><span class="text-dst">Because memory is divided into <strong>short-term memory</strong> and<strong> long-term memory</strong>, the way to convert short-term memory into long-term memory is to repeat over a period of time, rather than one at a time.</span></p>
<h2 class="textpanel-source active"><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">Sleep is a magic weapon that can make you smarter</span></h2>
<p><span class="text-dst">What are our brains doing while we sleep?</span><br><span class="text-dst">1. Clean up the garbage secretions produced by heavy exercise during the day.</span><br><span class="text-dst">2. Reorganize the information entered during the day, classify them and re-link them. </span><span class="text-dst">Suppose the brain is a large cabinet with many drawers, and the large amount of information entered during the day is like all kinds of things that have just been bought. </span><span class="text-dst">After going to bed at night, the brain classifies these things into various drawers one by one, so that you can use them later.</span><br><span class="text-dst">3. Strengthen the link between new knowledge and old knowledge, and subconsciously keep thinking about the problems that have not been solved during the day. </span><span class="text-dst">The most important thing is that these movements can only be done during sleep, so sleep is really an important task.</span></p>
<h2><span class="text-dst">To build a strong framework, you need two things, Chunking and Connecting</span></h2>
<p><span class="text-dst"><strong>Chunking</strong>, the knowledge we take in every day, like building bricks in a house, is independent. </span><span class="text-dst">If you want to build a house, you must have enough bricks, so it is necessary to learn all kinds of information.</span><span class="text-dst"> To build a house, you also need cement to connect these bricks. </span><span class="text-dst">This requires that every time you learn a knowledge, you should think about the causes and consequences of this knowledge, what are the rules, and so on.</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>Connecting</strong>, you will have the ability to innovate. </span><span class="text-dst">Because you can find a pattern in the connection of each small module. </span><span class="text-dst">Then as you have more and more connections and become more and more powerful, there will be more possibilities for connections. </span><span class="text-dst">The ability to innovate is coming.</span></p>
<h2><span class="text-dst hl">What to do when you need to learn something difficult</span></h2>
<p><span class="text-dst">First, if you need to learn something that is difficult,, don't focus on the results, enjoy the process. </span><span class="text-dst">Paying too much attention to the result will make you give up.</span><br><span class="text-dst">The second is to give yourself periodic rewards, which is very important. </span><span class="text-dst">Proper self-discipline is freedom, and excessive self-discipline is self-harm. </span><span class="text-dst">Your respect for human nature, respect for the nature of your brain, and a reward from time to time will make it easier for you to stick to it. </span><span class="text-dst">The interval between rewards should not be too long. </span><span class="text-dst">For example, if you lose weight for 5 days, you can eat freely; after 2 hours of homework, you can play with your cell phone for 10 minutes. After this reward, you are full of energy.</span><br><span class="text-dst">Third, believe in yourself and don't blame yourself all the time. </span><span class="text-dst">As long as this time is a little better than last time, it will be all right. </span><span class="text-dst">Of course, if it's not good once in a while, it doesn't matter, it's better next time.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
