<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>NOTELISH</title>
    <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii" />
    <updated>2021-04-29T17:41:37+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>one</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Get rid of the following five misunderstandings, and you will make progress faster</title>
        <author>
            <name>one</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/get-rid-of-the-following-five-misunderstandings-and-you-will-make-progress-faster/"/>
        <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii/get-rid-of-the-following-five-misunderstandings-and-you-will-make-progress-faster/</id>
            <category term="Progress"/>

        <updated>2021-04-29T17:41:37+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Indulge in things that are "easy to get a high sense of achievement" Consciously or unintentionally seek a recipe for a great "return" with a small amount of effort, even if the reward is virtual. This kind of behavior will raise their own "excitement&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <h2 id="indulge-in-things-that-are-easy-to-get-a-high-sense-of-achievement">
      Indulge in things that are "easy to get a high sense of achievement"
    </h2>

  <p>
    Consciously or unintentionally seek a recipe for a great "return" with a small amount of effort, even if the reward is virtual. This kind of behavior will raise their own "excitement threshold", making people less and less likely to have a sense of achievement, thus relying more and more on a virtual sense of achievement and falling into a vicious circle.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    Mild symptoms:&nbsp;"addicted to games" (speeding up the passage of time in the virtual world, so that "success" comes faster), "stallion novels" (obscene people can easily get what they want);
  </p>

  <p>
    Serious symptoms and even illegal: gambling" (easy access to "money"), "drug abuse" (easy to get the feeling of "cool"), and so on.
  </p>

    <h2 id="only-receive-sources-with-low-information-densitynbsp">
      Only receive sources with "low information density"&nbsp;
    </h2>

  <p>
    Only willing to receive information with low information density (such as videos and pictures that do not need too much brainstorming, as well as shallow entertainment, gossip, sports news, etc.). Do not want to receive information with high information density and can only be absorbed after careful consideration (such as courses, knowledge frameworks, analytical reports, etc.).&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    Since most of the really valuable and progressive information needs to be considered and digested, it will not be possible to make progress without in-depth study and understanding.
  </p>

    <h2 id="get-used-to-paralyzing-yourself-with-a-sense-of-misplaced-achievement">
      Get used to paralyzing yourself with a sense of "misplaced achievement"
    </h2>

  <p>
    <br>There are two categories: first, compare your strengths with other people's weaknesses, so as to get the illusion of "better than others" (for example, compared with athletes, and high achiever compared with sports); second, when others are resting after serious work, pretend to work harder (for example, "show off" that you have done more work than others on holidays, but only on holidays).
  </p>

    <h2 id="overreliance-on-existing-feasible-paths">
      Over-reliance on "existing feasible paths"
    </h2>

  <p>
    At work, after getting used to the process of a thing, I never think about how to improve it. I will only repeat it mechanically, and then deceive myself to be full. If there is no improvement, there is no consciousness of getting rid of dross, so there are more and more things that need to be repeated and take longer and longer. in the end, it seems that a lot of things have been done every day, but in fact, there is not only no progress at all. the time of progress that should have been made is also wasted.
  </p>

    <h2 id="close-the-channel-of-reinforcement-learning">
      Close the channel of "reinforcement learning"
    </h2>

  <p>
    In learning or receiving information, you are only willing to perform the simplest first step, but are unwilling to carry out the next more complex consolidation and application process, only listening without speaking, reading without writing, learning without practice, and paralyzing yourself by saying that you have learned a lot. In fact, this kind of "shallow" learning forgets so quickly that sometimes it is better not to learn at all. For example, learn English every day, but never write English articles.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to learn faster?</title>
        <author>
            <name>one</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/how-to-learn-faster/"/>
        <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii/how-to-learn-faster/</id>
            <category term="Study"/>

        <updated>2021-04-29T11:22:35+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are two modes of the human brain The two modes are the most efficient to use alternately. If you knock yourself to death in any mode, you are doing useless work. Focused mode: your brain is mainly learning, entering information, and doing information matching&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2><span class="text-dst">There are two modes of the human brain</span></h2>
<address><strong><span class="text-dst">The two modes are the most efficient to use alternately. If you knock yourself to death in any mode, you are doing useless work.</span></strong></address>
<p><span class="text-dst"><strong>Focused mode</strong>: your brain is mainly learning, entering information, and doing information matching work. </span><span class="text-dst">It is usually started when we are working and studying.</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>Diffuse mode</strong>: your brain is doing internal analysis, generating new links, re-linking and kneading old knowledge. </span><span class="text-dst">This state is initiated when we sleep, exercise and other relaxed states. </span><span class="text-dst">Sometimes you have inspiration when you take a shower, and that's what this pattern does.</span></p>
<p><span class="text-dst"> To sum up, it is necessary to stop and play after studying for a period of time. </span><span class="text-dst">It's not laziness, but only in this way, your brain works most efficiently.</span></p>
<h2>Procrastination is normal</h2>
<p><span class="text-dst">According to scientists, when we encounter something we don't like or something very difficult, the brain secretes a special substance that makes you feel uncomfortable. </span><span class="text-dst">Then it naturally encourages you to focus on other things, and you procrastinate. </span></p>
<p><span class="text-dst">So, first of all, you have to know that procrastination is a normal human behavior, so don't blame yourself too much. </span></p>
<p><span class="text-dst">What are we going to do with it? </span><span class="text-dst">Our brains also have a magical function, that is, once you focus on a task for more than five minutes, this particular substance will stop secreting. </span><span class="text-dst">So the solution to doing unhappy things is to force yourself to start for five minutes, and then everything will be fine.</span></p>
<h2><span class="text-dst">About memory. </span></h2>
<address><strong><span class="text-dst">The content needs to be repeated constantly, and the higher the previous repetition frequency, the longer the memory will be preserved</span></strong></address>
<p><span class="text-dst">Which of the following ways can achieve a better and faster memory effect if you want to remember a poem?</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>A</strong> memorize over 20 times a day.</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>B</strong> recite 10 times on the first day, 5 times on the second day, and 5 times on the 4th day.</span><br><span class="text-dst">The answer is <strong>B. </strong></span><span class="text-dst">Because memory is divided into <strong>short-term memory</strong> and<strong> long-term memory</strong>, the way to convert short-term memory into long-term memory is to repeat over a period of time, rather than one at a time.</span></p>
<h2 class="textpanel-source active"><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">Sleep is a magic weapon that can make you smarter</span></h2>
<p><span class="text-dst">What are our brains doing while we sleep?</span><br><span class="text-dst">1. Clean up the garbage secretions produced by heavy exercise during the day.</span><br><span class="text-dst">2. Reorganize the information entered during the day, classify them and re-link them. </span><span class="text-dst">Suppose the brain is a large cabinet with many drawers, and the large amount of information entered during the day is like all kinds of things that have just been bought. </span><span class="text-dst">After going to bed at night, the brain classifies these things into various drawers one by one, so that you can use them later.</span><br><span class="text-dst">3. Strengthen the link between new knowledge and old knowledge, and subconsciously keep thinking about the problems that have not been solved during the day. </span><span class="text-dst">The most important thing is that these movements can only be done during sleep, so sleep is really an important task.</span></p>
<h2><span class="text-dst">To build a strong framework, you need two things, Chunking and Connecting</span></h2>
<p><span class="text-dst"><strong>Chunking</strong>, the knowledge we take in every day, like building bricks in a house, is independent. </span><span class="text-dst">If you want to build a house, you must have enough bricks, so it is necessary to learn all kinds of information.</span><span class="text-dst"> To build a house, you also need cement to connect these bricks. </span><span class="text-dst">This requires that every time you learn a knowledge, you should think about the causes and consequences of this knowledge, what are the rules, and so on.</span><br><span class="text-dst"><strong>Connecting</strong>, you will have the ability to innovate. </span><span class="text-dst">Because you can find a pattern in the connection of each small module. </span><span class="text-dst">Then as you have more and more connections and become more and more powerful, there will be more possibilities for connections. </span><span class="text-dst">The ability to innovate is coming.</span></p>
<h2><span class="text-dst hl">What to do when you need to learn something difficult</span></h2>
<p><span class="text-dst">First, if you need to learn something that is difficult,, don't focus on the results, enjoy the process. </span><span class="text-dst">Paying too much attention to the result will make you give up.</span><br><span class="text-dst">The second is to give yourself periodic rewards, which is very important. </span><span class="text-dst">Proper self-discipline is freedom, and excessive self-discipline is self-harm. </span><span class="text-dst">Your respect for human nature, respect for the nature of your brain, and a reward from time to time will make it easier for you to stick to it. </span><span class="text-dst">The interval between rewards should not be too long. </span><span class="text-dst">For example, if you lose weight for 5 days, you can eat freely; after 2 hours of homework, you can play with your cell phone for 10 minutes. After this reward, you are full of energy.</span><br><span class="text-dst">Third, believe in yourself and don't blame yourself all the time. </span><span class="text-dst">As long as this time is a little better than last time, it will be all right. </span><span class="text-dst">Of course, if it's not good once in a while, it doesn't matter, it's better next time.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Configure Cloudflare Pages with Publii</title>
        <author>
            <name>one</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://litenotes.github.io/publii/111/"/>
        <id>https://litenotes.github.io/publii/111/</id>

        <updated>2021-04-29T09:04:02+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     All users of Cloudflare have access to Cloudflare Pages, which is an interesting alternative to regular static page hosting. And much like other hosting options with 'Page' at the end, we can use this service with Publii-based static websites in just a few simple&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="post__entry">
<p>All users of Cloudflare have access to Cloudflare Pages, which is an interesting alternative to regular static page hosting. And much like other hosting options with 'Page' at the end, we can use this service with Publii-based static websites in just a few simple steps. </p>
<h2 id="howitworks">How it works</h2>
<p>Without going into too much detail, the function of Cloudflare Pages is fairly simple. Once it has been set-up, it will connect to your GitHub repository; from then, every time you make a change on GitHub, Cloudflare Pages rebuilds your website using the data from GitHub. As you can probably guess, this means that in order to configure Cloudflare Pages with Publii you'll need both a GitHub and Cloudflare account.</p>
<h2 id="configuringyourgithubrepository">Configuring your GitHub repository</h2>
<p>The first thing you'll need to do is ensure that you have created a GitHub repository for your website that Publii can use to upload changes to your site. This is a fairly easy process, and you can find a detailed step-by-step breakdown on how to do it in our article about [GitHub deployment]([https://getpublii.com/docs/host-static-website-github-pages.html](https://getpublii.com/docs/host-static-website-github-pages.html)).</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning"><strong>Remember! </strong>As you won't actually be using GitHub Pages as the host of your site, you can create a Private repository rather than a Public repository. This will not have any effect on how your site performs on Cloudflare Pages, but it will prevent your website files being easily viewable as a repository on GitHub.</p>
<p>Your Cloudflare Pages website domain will usually default to <strong>GITHUB_REPOSITORY_SLUG.pages.dev</strong>,  so use this when setting-up your server details in Publii to ensure a smooth first sync. If you would prefer to use a custom domain name, you'll find details of how to configure this later in this article.</p>
<p>After setting up your GitHub repository, perform the first sync of your website to make sure that everything is working as it should; if the sync completes successfully, then you can move on to Cloudflare Pages configuration.</p>
<h2 id="settingupcloudflarepages">Setting up Cloudflare Pages</h2>
<p>Once your website is synced with GitHub, you can configure Cloudflare Pages.</p>
<ol class="list-spaces">
<li>Log in to your <a href="https://pages.cloudflare.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Cloudflare account</a> and select <strong>Pages</strong> from the right sidebar:
<figure class="post__image"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54//cloudflare-select-pages.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare select Pages" width="1456" height="679" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
<li>On the Pages screen, click on <strong>Create a new project</strong>:
<figure class="post__image with-border"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54//cloudflare-create-project.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Create a new Project" width="1456" height="679" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
<li>On the next screen, click on <strong>Connect GitHub account</strong>:
<figure class="post__image"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54//cloudflare-connect-github-project.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Connect Github Project" width="1456" height="917" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
<li>Here you'll see an authorization prompt, where you can select where the Cloudflare Pages app will have access on your GitHub account. You can restrict Cloudflare's access to only the repositories that you select here, so naturally you'll need to ensure your site's repository is selected. Once you've done this, click on <strong>Install &amp; Authorize</strong> to continue:
<figure class="post__image"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/autorize-cloudflare-pages-2.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Github Autorize Cloudflare Pages" width="1456" height="917" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
<li>In the next step, specify the GitHub account and repository to be used for your site, then click <strong>Begin setup</strong>:
<figure class="post__image"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/cloudflare-create-project-from-github.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloduflare Create a project from your GitHub repository" width="1456" height="1386" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
<p>During setup, you can set the project name (this will be used to create a website URL in the <em>.pages.dev subdomain</em>). Also, a production branch must be specified (it will be most probably <strong>main</strong> or <strong>master</strong>). When this is all configured, click <strong>Save and Deploy</strong>:</p>
<figure class="post__image"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/set-up-builds-and-deployments.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Set up builds and deployments with Cloudflare" width="1456" height="2214" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
<p>The deployment process will start; be aware that this may take a few minutes to complete, so don't worry if it seems a little slow. After the deployment process finishes, you may visit your website using the link displayed over the status message:</p>
<figure class="post__image"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/cloudflare-deployment-details.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Deployment details" width="1456" height="1926" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
<p>And, of course, your website will also be visible on the main subdomain; in the example this would be <em>cp-test.pages.dev</em></p>
</li>
<li>You may now review the status of your website by going back to the project page:
<figure class="post__image with-border"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/cloduflare-pages-status.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Pages Status" width="1456" height="885" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
</ol>
<p>If the auto-generated subdomain name you entered earlier was correct, and your GitHub repository slug was available - then you're all done! Your website is now available through Cloudflare Pages.</p>
<h2 id="howtosetupacustomdomainwithcloudflarepages">How to setup a custom domain with Cloudflare Pages?</h2>
<p>If you want to use your custom domain name, just follow these steps:</p>
<ol class="list-spaces">
<li>Open the <strong>Custom domains</strong> tab in site settings, and then click <strong>Set up a custom domain</strong>:
<figure class="post__image with-border"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/cloudflare-custom-domain.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Custom Domain" width="1456" height="816" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
<li>Enter the domain or subdomain which you want to use and click <strong>Continue</strong>:
<figure class="post__image with-border"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/cloudflare-add-custom-domain-2.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Add a Custom Domain" width="1456" height="876" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
<li>The rest of the process will depend on your domain settings - you can use Cloudflare's DNS service or configure a domain via your DNS provider:
<figure class="post__image with-border"><figure class="is-loaded"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://getpublii.com/docs/media/posts/54/cloudflare-setup-method.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Cloudflare Setup Method" width="1456" height="1331" loading="lazy"></figure></figure>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Using Cloudflare Pages is quite simple, and it's even easier if you already have an existing deployment of your site on GitHub as you'll then only need to configure Cloudflare Pages to work with your existing GitHub account. But if you haven't yet created a GitHub repository you'll find the process is not too demanding, and by following the steps outlined in this and the GitHub repository article linked previously, you can be up and running in no time. </p>
<p>As a final note, please do bear in mind that changes made to your website in Publii will not appear on the live site until a few minutes after each sync, as the whole process requires Cloudflare to sync up with GitHub first, and then run through its build process to actually update the site.</p>
</div>
<footer>
<div class="post__footer-top">
<div class="post__meta">Updated on: <time datetime="2021-03-17T06:35">March 17, 2021</time></div>
</div>
</footer>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
